so welcome back to the trt and hormone
optimization Channel and back with us as
a guest is Amir kouti welcome back
Amir I have to tell you Stephen you have
an accent and you say my name better
than anyone else that I've been
interviewed so a big kudos to You
Stephen for getting my name right so
thank you for that that must be just a
lucky shot I guess I guess so um first
of all thank you again for having me on
this is now my third time
I just want to say first and as I did
last time is how grateful I am of your
community what you've created the the
the professionalism of the doctors that
are on there the people that have helped
me out and so many others so if you guys
are not in the trt Facebook group uh I'm
a participant like anybody body else get
in there ask your questions if you have
any anything that you're thinking about
whether you're starting trt or having
issues get in the T trt Facebook group
it's amazing yeah sure we in this game
uh already a lot of years since 2018 I
created this Channel and the Facebook
group and Facebook group and um yeah
we've already helped a lot of people
we're not in this for the money we're
just in here to help other guys with the
same problems like we had before right
absolutely yeah absolutely so Amir was
on the channel before in an excellent
talk called post finite syndrome there
he shared his personal story and now
here his back with us because he has
some new insights and he has shared a
lot of his own experience with the guys
in the Facebook group so we're talking
about mental health Amir yeah and Ju
Just to let everyone know here I am not
a doctor I'm not a therapist I'm not a
counselor I'm just an ordinary human
being that went through a lot of stuff
and saw the light at the end of the
tunnel so I'm speaking to you from one
man to another from one human being to
another so I want to make that very
clear um this is not any medical advice
or anything like that so when you're
listening to this I want you to know I'm
one of you I want you to know that when
when you're listening to this act as if
you're speaking to someone and you're
going to a coffee shop or you're
listening and you might get something
out of this and whatever you get out of
this it's for you to keep right so get
listen to this conversation with an open
mind listen to this conversation without
your arms crossed and who is this guy
and what's he going to say and is he
going to change my mind if you're
already doing that it's not going to be
interesting so I want to make that very
clear
um I had post fastrite syndrome I think
around 10 years ago now right and on my
last call that I had I I was on with Dr
Keith blevens and before that I did a
PFS podcast I got a lot of incredible
emails I got messages on Facebook I got
phone calls I I reached out to people
and I wanted to hear what they got out
of of it and I found a common pattern a
very very similar pattern with whoever I
spoke to that's struggling mentally
right or they're struggling with PFS or
they're struggling with what they're
doing with their testosterone and so I
wanted to discuss that with us for the
next uh few minutes or whatever we have
the first thing is before I before I we
continue is if you are
suffering bear with yourself and be
patient number one like I I can't stress
that enough and I can't stress how much
how value that is to people that listen
to this and I'm going to remind you and
I'm going to remind myself again be very
patient and the and the first thing I
want to say with that is if you are
suffering okay if you are some suffering
get something out of your suffering
sounds like a very odd thing to say like
what does that mean get something out of
your suffering here's an example of you
of me of about 10 years ago when I had
PFS I knew this is going to be a long
journey my wife's sitting right next to
me right now she was a big Catalyst for
me where I'm at today but at the time I
did not know what I had I did not know
what's going on but I knew that I was a
mess the minute I found out I had
PFS the first thing I did is I got off
of social media where I became a
consumer of information where it was
simply everyone else is miserable they
don't know what to do do and they're in
in a bad negative state of mind I
already knew that about me so what I
decided to do I said you know
what I'm going to find out how I can
better myself I want to get out of this
suffering right and get something out of
this suffering so I called the uh I
emailed the PFS um Community H it's uh
PFS Foundation I said I want to be a
part of your community I want to do
something bigger let me do a podcast for
you guys and if you pull it up um I I
sent something to Dr Sten this was me 10
years ago this is one of my uh podcasts
that I did this was nine years ago it
says I'm sorry nine years ago and Dr
Greg Emerson is one of the doctors that
knew a lot about PFS and I believe he
had it as well so I ended up going and
speaking to all the international
doctors all over the world so instead of
becoming a consumer I said I'm going to
be in front of people and I'm going to
talk to the Top Doctors because I'm
going to find a solution now mind you I
could barely think at that time I could
barely form sentences but I was not
going to give up I wanted to find a way
out of this so I became in the center of
the universe and PFS now here's
something I want you guys to know now if
you looked at my last PFS video that I
did with uh uh Dr Stephen I was told on
the comments you've never had PFS you're
a you're a you're a shill you're trying
to do this for money I never made money
from this I I don't know why I would use
PFS to make money I it makes no sense to
me I did that nine years ago by the way
so I am not doing this since nine years
since nine years ago this has been the
most recent thing that I've done about
PFS for the nine years I didn't even
think about it right but what I want to
point out to is if you are suffering now
I'm not telling everyone here that's
suffering whether it's trt or if you
have post fastrite syndrome to go and
start going on podcasts but you can do
something immediately in this moment
what is that you can have a better
relationship with your wife or if you're
a female you can start being more
vulnerable with your husband if that's
something that you can do do that today
you can do small steps okay let's say
that you are struggling right now one of
the biggest gifts that I had with my
wife is I I when I was young I would go
to the gym all the time I didn't have
the muscle uh I had muscle I I was tired
I couldn't go to the gym but my wife
said don't go to the gym let's go
outside and take 10 steps you can take
10 steps and then the next day she'd say
you can do 20 steps she would not let me
sit at home and do nothing so what I'm
saying for you is if you are suffering
or if you're in your beginning journey
of your trt or whatever you're doing
whether it's your hormonal
imbalances do get something out of your
misery right
now get something out of your misery get
something positive out of it here's
another thing I did at that time I WR I
wrote a book called lessons for my coach
this is like about eight nine years ago
I have
one one little page on page 39 of the
book right here I wrote about my PFS
Journey that with the sexual side
effects and how I didn't have sex with
my wife for many years here's what's
funny this is a book about
coaching the most the most impact this
book had wasn't about all the lessons
about me coaching the biggest impact was
they said I don't have PFS but I'm
having mental issues about this I don't
have PFS but me and my I have my wife
just got cancer I have cancer and all of
a sudden I realize something we are all
struggling and trying to find the light
at the end of the tunnel at the end of
the day that's what is happening right
so you have an opportunity
to start becoming that light even in
your pain I know this sounds hard or it
might be difficult but you can do it
with a little bit of light just a little
bit right it's there's a saying I think
it was in a song that you just need a
little uh crack in your window for the
light to come in it doesn't have to be
fully open just a little crack and so
that's something that I want to start
off with I want you guys to just
consider that in your journey right now
because a lot of the calls I've gotten
is
I'm in pain and I need a solution today
I'm in pain I don't want to tell my wife
until I'm
fixed it's like well why would you do
that if if your wife is a confidant if
your wife is a partner then your part of
your healing is to share your journey
right now part of it is being vulnerable
in this moment and being able to tell
them hey this is what I'm going through
cuz let me tell you a secret there may
be something that she's going through
and she's held as well because she was
too afraid to tell you like just imagine
what kind of relationship you're
building when you go there first when
your honesty is the pathway for
something to change right like me and my
wife that's one of our biggest gifts is
we are so transparent with each other
the good the bad the ugly right and it's
been like that since my journey when we
didn't know what was going on with me
she knew that I couldn't have sex I I
didn't know why I just it it wasn't
working
and because I had such an amazing
partner she said we will figure it out
together it was a Wii right and so this
community for those listening right now
this is your Wii we are in this together
right now so when this call is done get
on the Facebook group and start sharing
your journey get on the Facebook group
and if you're already ahead of someone
start helping others in their Journey
right that's how we start getting better
this is not like well I don't know I
can't do anything right now you can like
Dr Steven DeVos you started this many
many years ago he didn't know how big
it's going to get he didn't know who's G
to follow him he didn't know that this
community is going to get so big he just
started putting things out to help
others now here we are my last one that
I did had 15,000 view some of his views
are in the hundreds thousands like it's
that's how you start you start with the
first stop mhm and you're not just
talking about post fenite syndrome
evidently you're talking about everyone
suffering with low testosterone and
whatever other hormonal issues right
everything whether it's hormonal issues
whether you have cancer whether you have
a uh posos if you have peos if you're a
lady it doesn't matter I'm just simply
talking about anyone and just mental
suffering even even if you're suffering
mentally mentally physically
psychologically spiritually right it
doesn't matter we're all we all like
this what what I'm talking about is an
equal opportunity
worldview we're humans we suffer and
working together we can find a way out
it's a simple as that and one of the
things I was thinking about like
Superman I had this discussion uh last
week the reason Superman we value
Superman or those Superman stories isn't
because he's always 100% with his s on
his uh chest and he's flying it's
because when he's down on Earth he works
in a newspaper organization he's a human
he's scared to ask the girl out at at
his office he he shares his his
vulnerabilities and then we get to
connect with him and say oh he's one of
us first and because we know he's one of
us he can now we can we can now can show
us his Superman powers I actually before
was before we got on this call I wanted
to get a quote that I saw that Clark
Kent said he said Clark Kent in the
movie said we all have something that
that we think we need to hide it's hard
but it does get better see he was able
to become Superman because he knew he
had to struggle first right we are all
superheroes we all have capes but when
we show our struggles when we show our
journey with people they get to see the
superhero inside right another quote
that I wanted to say uh this is Clark
Kent as well oftentimes a crisis has a
way of revealing a person's true nature
For Better or For
Worse right he decided to use his
struggles to help people right that's
what he did and I decided to use my
struggles for the same way I decided to
make my my relationship with my wife
better as best as I could now that I
have a daughter I I share her the
struggles that I went through when I was
younger so I can have a better
relationship with her and now I went on
your uh Facebook group and I helped
others and then one day I reached out to
you and said I'd love to do a podcast
and now I'm here nine years later on
another podcast still doing the same
thing right I did it when I was
struggling and I'm doing it still in my
journey nine years later still helping
others right but I didn't help others
until I was able to help myself until I
was able to slow down
enough to be able to see that I'm going
to be okay and that in my struggle I can
still work on myself I can still take
one step at a time I can still do just
the next step I don't have to know what
happens to me five years from now
whether I'm going to be cured whether
I'm going to be helped I just need to do
the first positive thing that's
available to me and if your first
possible available thing for you right
now is the fact that you clicked on this
video and you're listening to it
openhearted that's a win the fact that
you said in your struggle you know what
I still have the
capacity to go on YouTube and look for
something positive to listen to you're
already doing it because if you say to
me oh no I don't know if I can do it
you're listening right now and I hope
you're hearing this message loud and
clear so that's that's something that I
wanted to start um I can keep talking if
you want I can keep going or if you have
any questions
no that was the the first opener was the
next step in your uh struggle for uh
mental health I wrote some I wrote some
uh some some notes here's my notes this
is all I used for see what what comes up
the calls that I got from a lot of
people is they're on their they're on
their bottom of their Journey they're on
the lowest part of their Journey okay
and when they're on the lowest part of
their journey I notice them speak eating
up to get out of
it and what I've noticed in my
experience when we're in our lowest part
of our journey when we're in our heads
when we are
ruminating the best thing we can do is
slow down not speed up we slow down to
get connected to where we are that's why
the word grounding what does it mean to
be grounded is to be connected to
ourselves and I actually brought
something that you would say well what
does this have to do with with the
conversation
here's something really interesting um
this right here if you guys know what a
blow dryer is if you see this right this
is called a circuit interruptor on a
blow dryer every single blow
dryer that is made in the US I'm sure in
Europe and everywhere else has a circuit
interruptor and it's interesting that
it's naturally built in on a blow dryer
and you know what this does if you leave
it on for too long it will actually stop
itself from burning itself out it has a
mechanism so it doesn't burn itself out
or if it's in a dangerous place if you
put this in water it'll trip this before
it trips a circuit on your house that's
the wisdom of the design that's a
geniusly
built
mechanism here's something interesting
about us as humans we have that exact
same mechanism built in that's why it's
called depression when you have
depression what's the first thing it
does to you it makes you tired it tells
you to click puts you to sleep and it
makes it so you can't physically move
and it's telling you something slow down
it triggered something and it's
literally what the word is it's called a
circuit interruptor right it interrupts
your circuit to say stop doing what
you're doing I have people that called
me in the last few months but you don't
understand Amir I've been on these
forums and it's telling me this I know
stop getting on those forums but you
don't understand Amir I can't sleep so
the first thing I do is I get on my
phone and I have to find out why I feel
this way at two in the
morning well if you can't sleep at 2 in
the morning then get up and read go
listen to some calming music do
everything accept the thing that you
think you need to do that's not working
so slow down I just just had a call from
a gentleman yesterday and he reached out
and he said you know I'm on testosterone
awesome guy really really really
grounded he said I'm on
testosterone I um my sexual I'm 40 years
old and my sexual drive isn't where it's
been and should I get on more
testosterone you're on the cream should
I get on the cream that you're on should
I get on hcgs and I'm like well tell me
a little bit about your life and he
saidwell
I have three kids my work is stressing
me out by the time I get home I'm
exhausted and I said I have one daughter
and I have a wife and I have a business
that I'm running I'm exhausted when I
get home I'm not having sex three times
a day with my wife either you know I'd
love to but it's just life comes in the
way and I get exhausted and you had this
like this like moment of breath and said
oh holy crap I'm having a human moment
and I think everything is related to trt
or everything is related to I need to
increase my hormone or my dosage and all
that like folks this is a human game
this is a contact sport and everything
isn't purely medical like is your
psychological space healthy are you
coming home and are you exhausted and if
you are then look in that
space right do you have time to spend
time with your wife me and my wife how
many times have we said hey we need put
dates on the calendar and three months
passes and we're like oh my God we
haven't even spent 10 minutes together
right that's not a trt issue right
that's a relational issue that's a
taking time off to to spend time with
your wife issue and I'm know many you
guys sitting here are gonna say yes I
know what you mean right so slow
down slow down give yourself a little
bit of credit give yourself a little bit
of Grace
because you're going to have these kind
of times and when they come and hear me
like I feel
like I think the trt community was
probably the first me too movement and
what I mean by that is like when someone
comes to me and says I'm still exhausted
on trt I'm still feeling like this I'm
like well me too in the minute they hear
oh wait you you go through that too when
you're on trt like not everything is
perfect not everything is great like
you're not you actually still have to do
the work yes I still have to get up
and go to the gym I still have to get up
and eat good foods healthy foods yes I
still have to go to sleep and try to get
eight hours a night like all the stuff
that whether you're on trt or not you
still have to do and I promise you nine
out of the 10 people I speak to when I
say how are you eating well I'm not
eating that good because I'm not
sleeping well well do you think you
should work on that first I am but my
I'm working on my hematocrit I donate
blood and I'm like what are you talking
about like I again I'm not a doctor
maybe you need to do what you need to do
medically but find a qualified physician
to work on that stuff and you become a
qualified grounded human being and work
on your stuff and what is that stuff
again the simple stuff that's free
eating right sleeping right and and
taking care of
yourself right do those stuff I promise
you that you are not doing that I
promise you and if you are I promise you
you're sitting there and again the guy
that I spoke to said no I eat right I'm
trying to sleep but then he didn't
realize having three kids and a wife and
a full-time job that in of itself is a
lot on on your plate right and he again
that's that's something I just all these
are considerations for for you guys and
when I get these calls from the from the
guys it just reminds me
that we're all we all have our blind
spots we're all missing things that we
don't see and what a cool thing to
connect with other other men and be like
oh you know he's telling me this and I
go oh I'm doing that too right so again
you guys everyone here now there's going
to be trolls on on this YouTube uh video
I had them on my last video and the one
previous right you're going to have
trolls and those trolls I just want to
say something for you I feel for you you
have an opportunity that's my beautiful
wife that just left you have an
opportunity to either Troll And I it's
all right I'm just going to scroll by or
you have an opportunity to get on these
comment sections and write about your
experience share what you learned from
this reach out to another guy and say
Hey you know if you need help let me see
what we can do together or create a
community even if you can't help them
just have a community where you can say
hey I don't know the answers yet but
let's talk about our struggles together
like that's
how we Elevate
ourselves right these grown men that go
on YouTube to troll I don't understand
it but I feel for you because something
is missing for
you so that
is that's been on my mind that's that's
kind of where I wanted to discuss and
awesome yeah guys for you listening you
see that's exactly why we have Amir back
on the channel because I guess he's one
of the best motivational speakers we
have here yeah well I I appre I really
appreciate that and I'm I'm I'm not I'm
not a motivational speaker I'll just let
you know I just share what I know and
the impact of that in of itself again my
notes I didn't say much of what I wrote
my notes Here were simply um just to
just just to get me started
um the last thing I will say
um two things is a lot of men and a lot
of women that are having issues it's not
just a howto problem how do I get out of
this how do I find it's a being being
issue what do I mean by that it's who do
I need to be to find a solution for this
problem it's a very diff it's a very
slight variation I want I'm going to say
this again it's not how do I get out of
this issue that that that be that was
created because when I went to the how
too I went in from this from this pain
from this anger that I had from the
doctor that gave me this medicine from
from shame for not being able to have
sex with my wife there's all these
things but when I switched it to who do
I need to
be okay from that place I said well who
do I need to be in order to share this
message well I need to be a person that
needs to email the PFS foundation and
say I have a story to share and I want
to be the person running that that was
it there was nothing special about me I
don't have credentials I don't I'm not a
therapist I'm not a counselor I simply
said who I who do I need to be and I
reached
out again who do you need to be to be
one just one% better today than you were
yesterday who do you need to be not how
do I do it because when you get into the
house you start to question yourself I
don't know how to do it but you're being
we can be better we can do that right
now everyone listening that 1% change by
the time it's something that I learned
from my my uh my daughter's 8 years old
she has a Spanish teacher she said if
she learns one Spanish word a day by the
end of the year it's 365 words it
compounds right if you just one if
you're just 1% better a day it compounds
by 36 365 days you will not recognize
yourself see most of the people that I
speak to they want to get 50% better
they want to get 60% better they want to
change overnight but I'm going to tell
you right now I wish it worked that way
if I could figure that out if I had the
answer to that or Dr DeVos we'd be
millionaires right now it just doesn't
work that way it doesn't work like that
in my business it I would didn't become
a millionaire overnight didn't became my
relationship wasn't amazing overnight it
takes work and it takes Grace and it
takes patience
this is a long day game folks and in
your game in your journey if you're
waiting to be happy later then you're
doing it in the wrong
order start working on your happiness
right now start working on your
well-being right now and the worst
happens is uh and I'll give you one last
example before we go is I had a
gentleman that had postfastr Syndrome
from Europe he had his family was on the
line they were on their last resort they
didn't know what to do I asked the
parents what's going on with him he they
said he hides in his room days in and
days out he hasn't showered he hasn't
cut his hair he doesn't see his friends
so on on speaker I said uh to
him I want you to do something I'm not
going to tell you anything about my PFS
journey I said when's the last time you
got a haircut he's like I haven't gotten
a haircut in about eight months or a
year I don't remember
I said go get a haircut and come back
then I'll call I'll talk to you so he
goes I don't know what this has to do
with anything so he went got a haircut
and he called me back and I said let and
then I asked his parents did you get a
haircut and he said yes Amir he got a
haircut I said good I
said when you got your haircut were you
depressed he said yes nothing changed I
said I want you to notice something you
can get a haircut even when you're
depressed I said I'm going to I I'll
share you my secret with PFS once you
get back I want you to go on a walk and
come back he's like you're kidding me so
he went on a walk and came back he said
now what I said did you go on a walk he
saides I said were you depressed he says
yes nothing changed I said I want you to
realize something you can go on a walk
and still be depressed in other words
you can still do the activities you need
to do you can't stop living life until
you get better because at the end of the
day listen ladies and gentlemen at the
end of the day we're doing all this
stuff to live a wonderful life but what
a shame it is we're stopping our life
until that gets better to live it like
start cultivating a wonderful life right
now because as you build that muscle of
positivity and
strength it becomes easier to live that
wonderful life and then the worst
happens is in a you still haven't had
your answer that was me I didn't have an
answer about PFS for for many years I
didn't get resolved for many years but I
started Living a wonderful life as I was
looking for the answers as I was
searching for the answers there are so
many people that call me and say I can't
I I can't even look at my wife until I
feel better like what a
shame what a shame I can't I here I
can't I can't I won't it's impossible to
a week later the
gentleman that said he couldn't get a
haircut that couldn't walk he started
working out I said hey are you serious
you worked out he goes yeah he goes I
felt like crap but I went to the gym and
he got he noticed
something his psychology he realized can
be irrelevant to what he can do in the
world I'm going to say that again not
all the time I'm not saying 100% of the
time there's times where just like what
I said with this you just need a rest
but when you have a moment where you can
do something take that opportunity to do
it he started texting me and saying I
started going out to the bars I started
meeting my friends he got a glimpse he
had just a little bit of light coming in
and he started noticing something he
started going back to life he started
going to the bars again with this
friends he started going out with his
family and he said yeah I still feel
depressed every once in a while but it's
starting to become easier and this isn't
his
words because I'm starting to go back
and doing the things I stopped doing and
I realized something how much I was
missing now I haven't spoken to him
since I don't know if he's gotten better
but I hope if you're listening to this
you're still going out with your friends
you're still getting your haircuts
you're still working out and you're
still improving
yourself as you're dealing with whatever
issues you are dealing because at the
end of the day we're all going to have
more issues to deal with and we can
either go on the side of trying to
figure that out for the rest of our
lives which is going to be a game we're
going to be playing for the rest of our
lives or becoming 1% better as we
continue that Journey great talk uh
excellent advice Amir thank you so much
yeah excellent Stephen thank you again
for having me I hope this was useful
again leave comments on on the YouTube
uh video it I read all of them the ones
as much as I can I read them all I try
to reply to those uh ones that are
positive or have questions for me uh you
can reach out to me you can find me my
name is Amir kudi if you have any
questions and uh Stephen again I'm so
grateful for you I'm grateful for your
community for those again that are
listening go to the community ask your
questions ask your questions on the
YouTube channel he does this again he's
a doctor he he has a job outside of this
and he does this simply for us for us to
connect for to learn for us all to grow
and learn from each other so again thank
you Stephen for everything that you do
don't mention it Amir thank you have a
great day thank you you too man thank
you